KAYLEN MILLINER

WEB DEVELOPMENT / SOFTWARE TESTING

E: kaylen.milliner@gmail.com // www.kaylenmilliner.com

RELEVANT SKILLS

TECHNOLOGY

Study of web development for over a year including HTML5, CSS3, and some JavaScript and Ruby. Website administration and content editing on Wordpress site. Experience with graphic design tools in Adobe Creative Suite.

LEADERSHIP

Led a Communications department which included supervision of an employee and delegation of tasks to meet departmental and organizational goals. Provided feedback, guidance, and training to employee. Led several trainings and workshops, including technology update trainings and a seminar class to help build understanding amongst intergenerational co-workers.

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Coordinated three annual conferences with over 400 attendees each and three annual fundraising events with contributions totaling approximately \$200k. Coordinated two annual health fairs attended by 150 participants and 20 vendors providing wellness education and insurance benefit information. Assisted in coordinating the first Cincinnati ReelAbilities Film Festival attend by over 500 people. Managed a team of 25 new volunteers by delegating tasks to assist disabled attendees and honorees at a major gala event.

COMMUNICATIONS

Created a full re-branding campaign to better communicate to 35,000 members, garnering an increase in social media followers and 15% increase in engagement. Increased insurance plan wellness engagement by 20% with a wellness initiative marketing campaign reaching over 10,000 benefit plan participants. Utilized Constant Contact software to create a dynamic email marketing campaign which drove more than 200 recipients to make donations. Organized and lead 15 presentations in different locations to educate participants about their benefits.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

2019 - Present SELF-EMPLOYED - Communications Consultant
2016 - 2019 UFCW LOCAL 75 - Communications Director
2014 - 2014 APPLE - At-Home Technical Advisor

2013-2013 LADD, INC. - Development Assistant

2010-2012 UFCW LOCAL 75 BENEFIT PLAN - Communications Coordinator

EDUCATION

2019-2021 FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

Lambda School

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React, Python, Express, SQL

2003 - 2007 BA COMMUNICATIONS

BA FILM STUDIES

University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA



STATEMENT

I am transitioning into a career in Tech and working toward becoming a Full Stack Web Developer. My love for code came about over a decade ago while taking a basic web design class. Over the years, I have done a great deal of work in Administrative and Communications roles that have given me insight into great customer experiences and how to better engage and inform people. I've worked in many different industries and learned to adapt my skillset along the way.

Making processes more efficient and beneficial is one of my passions, and I plan to make it a focus throughout my career in technology. I love learning and I'm a student for life. The challenge that comes with learning new languages and systems is exciting for me. I want to help make web experiences better for all users and help build software that improves the way we live everyday.

My skills and experience are transferrable, and I would like to bring value to your team in a testing or development capacity.

SKILLS

- Attention to detail and organization
- Creative problem solving and critical thinking
- Ability to quickly learn new skills and processes
- Great on teams, contributing to projects, and providing feedback
- Communicating with clients and understanding their needs
- Project planning, task prioritization and delegation